Hello it's Scott Manley here.
你好 我是Scott Manley
This week a movie trailer appeared which well I really want to talk about.
本周发布了一个电影预告片 我真的想谈谈它
Not because I think it's a good movie
不是因为我认为它是一部好电影
but because it poses an interesting question.
而是因为它提出了一个有趣的问题
The movie is moonfall
这部电影是《月球坠落》
and it features a moon sliding just across the surface of the earth as if it were in low earth orbit.
并且它的重头戏是 月亮在地球表面滑动 就像它在低地球轨道上一样
So I wanted to basically show what it would take to do that.
因此 我想基本上展示出要做到这一点需要什么
And of course mock the movie a little as we're doing at.
当然 在我们做这些的同时 也会对电影进行一些模拟
So this is a system called universe sandbox.
所以现在展示的 是一个叫做宇宙沙盒的系统
It's basically a gamified simulation of the universe.
它基本上是一个游戏化的宇宙模拟
and you can load up a simulation of the solar system
并且 你可以加载一个太阳系的模拟
and we can select the moon and we can go into its motion and adjust its velocity
而我们可以选择月球 并且我们可以设置它的运动 调整它的速度
so that's what we're going to do.
所以这就是我们将要做的
Now we want to bring it down so that it passes just above the surface of the earth.
那么 我们想把它降下来 使它刚好经过地球表面
We want to get its pericenter distance to about 9000.
我们想让它的近心点距离达到约9000
That means if you add the radius of the moon in the earth they do not collide.
这意味着如果你把月球和地球的半径加在一起 它们不会相撞
So I'm going to drag this down.
所以我打算把这个拖下来
Now the initial speed is about one kilometer per second.
现在的初速度大约是每秒1公里
We're probably going to have to drop it down to about 200 meters per second
我们可能要把它降到每秒200米左右
to get our velocity low enough that
才能使我们的速度足够低
it just skims over the surface of the earth for a maximum cinematic dramatic effect.
使月球只是在地球表面滑过 以获得最大的电影戏剧效果
Now the simulation is running in real time right now.
现在 这个模拟正在实时运行
In fact it's running with today's date.
事实上 它是以今天的日期运行的
But I can click this to run the thing faster.
但我可以点击这个来加速运行
I have to remember however to slow it down once we get close.
然而 我必须记住 一旦它们开始接近时 就要把它放慢
And once it gets close we want to slow things down
而一旦它接近了 我们要把运行速度放慢
so we can actually observe the destruction in extreme detail.
这样我们就能真正观察到破坏的极端细节
The main thing that's going to drive this destruction isn't the impact
驱动这种破坏的主要因素不是冲击力
because you're not going to have these things impact.
因为这些东西之间不会有冲击力
We've adjusted it to make sure that doesn't happen.
我们已经调整了它 以确保这不会发生
What is going to happen is the gravitational forces are going to stretch both objects
将要发生的是 引力将拉伸两个物体
and you're going to have extreme tides.
而你将会看到极端的潮汐
You're going to have stretching of the bodies.
你将会看到 天体们会被拉伸
And that's actually going to cause earthquakes on earth.
而这实际上将导致地球上的地震
Massive tidal effects. You're going to have water flows inundating the surface
大规模的潮汐效应 你将会看到水流淹没地表
and of course a whole bunch of other stuff that will really soak up your VFX budget.
当然还有一大堆其他的东西 那些都将真正耗尽你的视觉特效预算
The moon on the other hand it comes off even worse.
在另一方面 月球的情况更糟糕
洛希极限(Rochelimit)是一个天体对自身的引力与第二个天体
对它造成的潮汐力相等时两个天体的距离。当两个天体的距离
少于洛希极限，天体就会倾向碎散，继而成为第二个天体的行星环。
它以首位于1848计算这个极限的法国天文学家爱德华·洛希命名。
It actually gets torn apart as it flies inside the roche limit.
实际上 当它在洛希极限内飞行时 它被撕碎了
It'll have debris pulled off the surface and that stuff will go into different orbits.
它将有碎片被拉出表面 并且这些东西将进入不同的轨道
Now some of this stuff is actually going to go into an orbit that brings it back to earth
那么 这些东西中的一部分 实际上会进入一个会将其带回地球的轨道
so if I select the planet earth and we drag this down
所以 如果我选择地球 并且我们把这个拖下来
so you can see the simulation.
这样你就可以看到模拟的情况
Oh well let's do this.
让我们这样做吧
Yeah so we can see the simulation.
是的 所以我们可以看到模拟的情况
Oh. Yeah we've already had one impact there.
哦是的 我们这里已经有一个撞击了
Oh just skimming by past.
啊啊啊 哦 这个刚刚略过了过去
I'm surprised those missed.
我很惊讶 这些都错过了
That was a close shave.
这是个很好的例子
Now at this point everywhere on the planet earth is getting seriously damaged.
那么 在这时 地球上的所有地方都受到了严重破坏
Not just from the impacts
这些破坏不仅仅是来自撞击
but just by the fact that we have put so much energy into the system with this close pass.
而只是因为 我们在这次近距离通过时向地月系 投入了如此多的能量
You have to imagine that this kind of gravitational disruption
你必须想象 这种引力的扰动
will probably move the crust and the mantle around enough that
可能会使地壳和地幔发生足够的移动 以至于
it will cause a lot of energy that's built up in fault lines to release.
它将导致大量积聚在断层线上的能量释放
You'll have earthquakes all over the world.
世界各地将发生地震
As I said that's the task for the VFX artist.
正如我所说 这些是视觉特效艺术家的任务
So look this is not good.
所以你看 这不是好事
The average temperature on the planet earth is now almost 100 degrees centigrade.
现在 地球上的平均温度几乎是100摄氏度
Granted that is largely because there are some very hot areas
的确 这主要是因为有一些非常热的地区
while the rest of the earth is merely wondering why it's flooded.
与此同时 地球的其他地方 只是在困惑我们为什么会被淹了
The moon on the other hand if we select the moon it's got very hot
另一方面 如果我们选中查看月球 它变得非常热
and the way that is just the simulation had a lot of the stuff that's pulled off it.
而这的原因只是 在模拟中 月球上的很多物质被扯掉了
Has now come back and hit the moon and that sort of raised its temperature
这些东西现在又回来了 并击中了月球 而这就提高了它的温度
along with the energy released by the gravitational interactions the the tidal effects.
与引力相互作用和潮汐效应释放的能量一起
木卫一 艾奥(Io) 是木星的四颗伽利略卫星中最靠近木星的一颗卫星，
其直径为3,642公里，是太阳系第四大卫星。
Remember the moon Io around Jupiter.
记得木星周围的卫星艾奥吗
It is kept hot by these gravitational interactions with the tides.
这些相互作用引力和潮汐效应释放的能量 使它保持高温
And in fact it's got so hot now that it is starting to boil
而事实上 月球现在已经变得如此之热 以至于它开始沸腾了
and you've got like a cometary tail in this case.
而在这种情况下 你会有一个像彗星那种的尾巴
I'm not sure how accurate that is.
我不确定这有多准确
But it does bring me to the question of
但它确实给我带来了这样一个问题
how we would actually get 800 meters per second of delta v from the moon or to push the moon around.
我们如何从月球上获得每秒800米的Dv 或者说用它向周围推动月球
So if you think about the best rocket engines we have are the RL-10.
所以如果你想一下 我们拥有的最好的火箭发动机是RL-10
That's a hydrogen oxygen rocket engine.
那是一个氢氧火箭发动机
Scott这里有问题 RL-10的比冲应该都在400s以上
要用于火神火箭的最新版本RL10C-1-1 比冲为453.8 s
And it gets about 370 seconds of specific impulse.
而它能创造大约370秒的比冲
So if you do the math on that
因此 如果你基于它进行计算
you would need about one quarter of the moon's mass in propellant to fuel this thing.
你将需要质量大约为月球四分之一的推进剂 来为这个东西提供燃料
And that's a problem because it uses hydrogen and oxygen
而这是一个问题 因为这个发动机使用的是氢气和氧气
so the obvious place to get that hydrogen oxygen is the oceans of the earth.
所以能获取氢气和氧气的明显地点 是地球上的海洋
Well the oceans of the earth are about 10% of the mass of the moon.
地球上海洋的质量 大约是月球质量的10%
Therefore there's not enough
因此 这里没有足够的海洋
if you took all the oceans on the earth and converted it to rocket propellant
如果你把地球上所有的海洋转化为火箭推进剂
and then shipped it up to the moon
然后把它们运到月球上去的话
you would not have enough propellant to do this.
你还是将没有足够的推进剂来做这件事
What you really need to do is find some sort of local propellant that is easier and more useful.
而你真正需要做的是 找到某种本地推进剂 这更容易 并且更有用
There's not enough water in the moon to do this.
月球上没有足够的水来做这件事
There is another option is to use a higher more efficient thruster
还有一个选择是使用更高效的推进器
because one of the problem with chemical thrusters is that
因为化学推进器的问题之一是
their velocity is comparable to the escape velocity of the moon.
它们的速度与月球的逃逸速度相当
The moon's escape velocity is about two kilometers per second.
月球的逃逸速度约为每秒两千米
That means you lose two kilometers per second off your exhaust velocity
这意味着你的排气速度每秒减少了两千米
because it has to fight against gravity.
因为它必须与重力作斗争
That cuts the performance of your RL-10 in half.
这使你的RL-10的性能减半
There's other chemical propulsion systems that you could use that don't use hydrogen and oxygen.
还有其他化学推进系统你可以使用 它们不使用氢气和氧气
There's things like aluminium oxygen where you would take alumina found in the lunar crust
有像氧化铝这样的东西 你可以把在月球地壳中找到的氧化铝
break it into aluminium and oxygen and use that as a rocket.
将其分解成铝和氧 并将其作为火箭燃料使用
But that is even lower performance.
但这的性能甚至更低
A better idea is something called the magnesium hall effect thruster.
一个更好的想法 是一个叫做镁燃料霍尔效应推进器的东西
And this is something that's been investigated I'm not sure it's been built
并且这是一个已经被研究过的东西 我不确定它是否已经被制造出来
but I know that Busek who make regular hall effect thrusters using xenon and krypton
但我知道 制造使用氙气和氪气的常规霍尔效应推进器的Busek公司
they've demonstrated or they've talked about this with magnesium
他们已经证明了 或者说他们已经谈到了使用镁的这个问题
you can get specific impulse of about 4000 seconds.
你可以用它得到大约4000秒的比冲力
That means the exhaust velocity is 40 kilometers per second
这意味着排气的速度为每秒40千米
so losing two kilometers from the moon's gravity isn't such a big deal.
所以 由于月球的重力从中损失两公里并不是什么大问题
And with that very high performance
而且 在这种非常高的性能下
you would only need about two percent of the mass of the moon to do this.
你只需要大约百分之二月球质量的推进剂就可以做到这一点
So the next question is is there enough magnesium on the moon.
因此 下一个问题是月球上是否有足够的镁
And looking at the geology from the surface and analysis
而观察月球表面的地质情况 并分析来看
it does seem that there's probably enough oxygen in the moon.
看来 月球上是可能有足够的氧
On the other hand you would probably have to mine most of the moon
在另一方面 你可能必须开采大部分的月球
to actually access it to extract out the small part that is magnesium.
才能真正开采出那一小部分的镁
On the other hand if you could make a thruster that worked with pure oxygen
而在另一方面 如果你能制造一个能用纯氧工作的推进器
an ion thruster that would be great
也就是一台离子推进器 那就太好了
because oxygen is one of the biggest components of the moon by weight.
因为按重量来说 氧是月球质量上最大的组成部分之一
On the other hand trying to run an engine using ionized oxygen
而在另一方面 试图用离子化的氧气驱动发动机
is just asking for engine rich exhaust.
会使发动机的排气量巨大
Well the point is it's not going to happen.
但重点是 这些是不可能发生的
but of course in the movie they need it to happen.
但当然 在电影中他们需要它发生
What do they do.
他们是怎么做的
They use aliens and aliens are a completely possible way to cause the moon to fall to earth.
他们利用外星人 而外星人是导致月球落到地球上的一个完全合理的方法
They don't need to obey the laws of physics.
他们不需要遵守物理学定律
In fact if I had looked at this trailer and been asked to rate on realism
事实上 如果我看了这个预告片 并被要求对现实性进行评分的话
I would have said the most unrealistic thing was having the Space Shuttle flying in 2022.
我会说最不现实的事情是 让航天飞机在2022年飞行
Now I've been working on the basis that it took 800 meters per second of delta v
那么 我上述讨论的基础是 它需要每秒800米的Dv
but it turns out that because the moon is so far away
但事实证明 由于月球离我们如此之远
we can use something called a bi-elliptic transfer.
我们可以使用一种叫做双椭圆转移轨道的东西
That is a clever little exploit in the laws of physics.
这是在物理学规律中 一个聪明的小开发
That helps us get a little more bang for our buck
这有助于我们获得更多的收益
if we're prepared to take a bit more time.
如果我们准备多花一点时间的话
So this is just the earth and the moon so I can demonstrate it.
所以这只是地球和月球 所以我可以演示一下
What we're going to do instead is boost it up to a very highly eccentric orbit
我们要做的是把它提升到一个高度偏心的轨道上
a long way from the earth
在离地球很远的地方
and then we'll slow it down and it turns out this needs less delta v
然后我们把它放慢 结果发现这需要更少的Dv
so if I take this we're going to push the semi-major axis and the pericenter distance out as far as we can
所以如果我用这种方式 我们要把半长轴和近心点的距离尽可能地推远一些
so that it's moving very very slowly.
这样 它就会非常非常缓慢地移动
And the most this will take us is about 400 meters per second.
而这最多需要每秒400米左右的Dv
Now look I've pushed the apocenter distance to undefined.
现在看 我已经把远心点距离推到了未定义
That means it's now on uh on an orbit which is parabolic or hyperbolic.
这意味着它现在在一个抛物线或双曲线的轨道上
It will never come back to earth
它将永远不会回到地球上来
because it's exceeded escape velocity.
因为它已经超过了逃逸速度
So I need to slow this down just a bit
所以我需要把这个速度放慢一点
until we get the apocenter to be redefined
直到我们得到重新定义的远地点
and you'll notice the semi-major axis is negative in this.
而你会注意到 半长轴在这里是负的
This is just a consequence of the mathematics modeling these conic sections.
这只是为这些圆锥截面数学建模的结果
There we go.
好了
That is an extremely highly eccentric orbit that goes out to 0.45 au.
这是一个极其高度偏心的轨道 其一直延伸到0.45天文单位
It's going to take years to get there in this simulation
在这个模拟中 要花数年时间才能变成这样
but the good news is that we only spent 400 meters per second to do this.
但好消息是 我们只花了每秒400米的Dv来做到这个
Okay so here we are about 30 years later
好了 所以我们到了 大约30年后
and the moon because we've pushed it out on this orbit
而月球 因为我们把它推到了这个轨道上
it's moving at only 8.4 meters per second
它的移动速度只有每秒8.4米
so it takes a tiny amount of velocity
所以它需要一个很小的速度
to slow it down enough that it will now pass very close to or hit the earth.
来使它足够慢下来 使它现在会非常接近或撞击地球
And it only took about 400 meters per second to push it up here
而我们只用了每秒400米的Dv就把它推到了这里
so there's a sort of basic rule if you can do like a bi-elliptic transfer
所以这里有一种基本的规则 如果你能进行像双椭圆轨道的转移
then the minimum delta v to reach any target is the escape velocity, right.
那么到达任何目标的最小Dv 就是逃逸速度 对吗
Because that's your sort of the limit on this.
因为那是你在这方面的极限
So yeah if I want to bring the pericenter distance down to the surface of the earth.
所以是的 如果我想把近心点的距离降低到地球表面
Doesn't take very long.
这并不需要很长的时间
It takes a few meters per second.
每秒只需要几米
Now this only works when we've got the earth and the moon
那么 这只在我们只有地球和月球的情况下有效
because if we try to push something up to this highly eccentric orbit
因为如果我们试图把东西推到这个高度偏心的轨道上
as it's out so far away from the earth it won't escape the earth's gravity
因为它离地球太远了 虽然它将无法逃脱地球的引力
but other planets influence will become more important than the earth
但其他行星的影响将变得比地球的影响更为重要
and they will pull it off in its own weird directions.
而且它们会把这个东西 拉到它自己的奇怪方向上
Now that doesn't mean we can't make the moon hit the earth.
那么 这并不意味着我们不能让月球撞击地球
It just means that we can't use this very simple formulation.
它只是意味着我们不能使用这个非常简单的公式
It's going to take a lot more cout math and a lot more calculus and simulation
这将需要更多的数学计算 更多的微积分和更多的模拟
to bring the object into an orbit where we know that we'll hit the earth.
来把这个物体带入一个我们知道它会撞击地球的轨道
So here it's coming back down now.
所以在这里 它现在又下来了
And I have to be careful.
而我必须要小心
I don't make this happen too fast.
我不会让这一切发生得太快
The orbital period is 60 odd years
轨道周期是60年左右
because you've got earth type gravity.
因为你有地球类型的引力
Whoa and there we slung by.
哇 它在那里滑过去了
You see I messed it up.
你看 我把它搞乱了
But this is a simulation so I can rewind
但这是一个模拟 所以我可以回放
and we can watch the moon get torn apart again if that's your thing.
我们可以再看一次月球被撕碎 如果你喜欢的话
Now this isn't hollywood VFX quality.
那么 这不是好莱坞的视觉特效质量
In fact the fidelity of the simulation is missing a lot of stuff.
事实上 模拟的逼真度缺少很多东西
Everything is still treated as point masses more or less.
所有东西都或多或少仍被视为点状质量
There is a type of simulation called smoothed particle hydrodynamics
有一种叫做平滑粒子流体力学的模拟方法
which is basically a way of modeling fluidized bodies
那基本上是一种对流化体进行建模的方法
under self-gravity and close gravitational interaction
根据自重和密切的引力相互作用
so the earth can be treated as a fluid.
因此 地球可以被看作是一种流体
I mean after all most of it is more or less liquid rock under the right conditions.
我的意思是 毕竟在适当的条件下 它的大部分或多或少都是液体岩石
And one of the developers of universe sandbox
而宇宙沙盒的一个开发者
did smooth particle hydrodynamics simulations for his postgraduate work.
在他的研究生工作中做了流畅的粒子流体力学模拟
And about 18 months ago the devs of universe sandbox showed off some smooth particle codes.
并且在大约18个月前 宇宙沙盒的开发者展示了一些光滑粒子代码
They weren't properly integrated it with the rest of the system.
他们并没有将其与系统的其他部分适当地整合
I would love to see that
我很想看到这一点
because I would love to be able to crash the planets together with greater fidelity and detail
因为我希望能够以更高的逼真度和细节 将行星撞在一起
and frankly
并且坦率地说
I'm looking forward to that being in universe sandbox more than I'm looking forward to a movie called moonfall.
比起电影《月球坠落》 我更期待这项功能在宇宙沙盒中的出现
I'm Scott Manley. Fly safe.
我是Scott Manley 切记 注意飞行安全
[Music]
[音乐]